Hello everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're watching You the Real.  I am
your personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma.
In today's video we will learn about the Income Protection Plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited.
Income Suraksha Plan from Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited is a term
insurance plan that has two different
variants.  The first is fixed income
protection.  The second is increasing income
protection.  Both these options
work in different ways.  As a result,
you can take only one option while purchasing the plan.   The
age limit for taking the plan is from 21
years to 55 years.  The maturity age
limit is minimum 31 years and maximum 70
years, that is,
you can remain under the cover of this plan till the maximum age of 70 years.
Under Limited Pay, you get the option of premium payment term of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years,
12 years, 15 years and 20 years,
in which the
minimum policy term becomes premium payment term
plus 5 years.
In case of regular premium payment term, the minimum policy term is
10 years.  Regular pay means paying
premium continuously for the number of years the positivity is maintained.  The
maximum positivity you get is 49 years i.e. 49
years.  Now the
model factor is given here.  Model factor
means that an extra charge is levied on the
premium.  If you pay the
premium in annual installments, then model factor
charge is not applicable.  If you pay in installments, then
4% interest will be charged on your premium and if you pay quarterly, then
6% will be charged.  If you pay in monthly installments,
8% will be charged.
This is charged on top of the one year premium.  The minimum sum
assured you get in this is up to ₹25 lakh.  The
maximum sum assured limit in this is
₹2 crore.
How much the insurance company allows you depends
on your eligibility.  ok sir.   The
minimum income limit is that
while taking the plan, you have to choose the income benefit
that you want every month, its
minimum limit is ₹20833.33.
Talking about discount, if
you choose annual income of ₹5 lakh or more, only then
you will get a discount of 7% on the first premium.
If you are male or transgender,
if you are female, you will get a discount of 9% on the first premium.  The
grace period is
15 days with the monthly mode.
With other modes of premium, you get a
grace period of 30 days.  Grace
period is an extra time period
that starts after the due date in
which you can pay the premium and the
policy remains in force.  Ok?  Let us
now know about the benefits of Income Protection Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance.
So there are only two variants.  The
first is fixed income protection.
If you take fixed income protection, you will
not get any survival benefit.  There is no
maturity benefit available as it is not there
in the plan and if there is no share then it will
not be available.  If there is a death benefit, then it will be the
sum assured on death amount that you have taken at the time of
taking the plan or let us
understand in simple words that the monthly income that
you have decided at the time of taking the plan, that in
your absence, the nominee will get it either
till the end of the policy term or for 120 months, whichever is
higher from
the date of death.  If you multiply the
monthly income you are getting as per the sum assured in the plan
by 120, then the sum
assured amount will come out.  For an
example, the policy brochure shows that
Mr. Bhatt is 35 years old.
He is a non-smoker.  He took Income Protection Plan from Aditya
Birla Sunlife Insurance Company Limited
with Option Number One Fixed Income Protection.  He
wants a monthly income benefit of ₹1 lakh.
If he is no more, his nominee will continue to receive it.  The
policy term is 30 years.
He is also taking the premium payment term of 30 years.
Right?  So in this case, he will
pay a premium of ₹21,720 every year.  Now, it is mentioned here
in the policy brochure that if Mr. Bhatt
dies in the middle of the 15th year of the policy,
as it is written during, then
his nominee will start getting the monthly income benefit of ₹1 lakh from the date
of death, when the death claim is filed and the right is
approved.
How long it will take to get?  You will get it for 180 months
because brother, there are 12 months in a year, so you will get it for
15 years.  Right?  So it is worth ₹1
lakh.  I am getting it every month.  If you
multiply it by 180, the amount becomes ₹1 crore 80 lakh.
Ok?  The next
option in this is Increasing Income
Protection.  Now we will
talk about increasing income protection here.  So there
is no maturity benefit here also.  Sir, there is
no royal benefit.  There is only death benefit
as it is a term plan.  Ok?
What will happen if you take this option is that the monthly
income that you have chosen while taking the plan will keep
increasing at the rate of 5% every year.  The
company will continue to compound.  Ok?  And how
long will this continue?  Until your monthly income becomes one and a half
times.  Ok?  It will happen only till then.   It wo
n't happen after that.  That means if you are getting ₹1 lakh then
it will increase to ₹1.5 lakh.   You wo
n't get it after that.  The sum
assured on death in the plan is because a provision has been made in the plan
that if the nominee
wishes, he can take the lump sum amount and close the plan.
So in such a situation, the amount of sum assured
on death can also be seen.
Like you can do it 11 times the annual premium.
Get 105% of the premium you paid till the date of death.  Some Ashard I have already
told you.  Absolute amount
assured to be paid on that means the
total sum of monthly income benefit.
Now, whichever is higher among all these would be the
sum much order on death.  Now the
example given in the policy brochure is
Mr. Kapoor who is 35 years old.
They want a minimum base income of ₹1 lakh per month
that the nominee must
receive.  He has chosen the policy term premium payment term of
30 years only.
With Increasing Income Protection option
which is option number two of the plan.  So
in this case, he will pay a premium of ₹31,440 every year.
Now it is believed that
Mr. Kapoor died
during the fifth year.  That means the fifth year has
not been completed.  Four years were completed and the
fifth year started and it happened.  So, the
first monthly income benefit that their nominee will
get will be ₹121550.
If it continues to grow in the future, how long will it continue to
grow?  This will increase only till the 10th year of the policy
because by then the monthly income benefit will have increased by
one and a half times i.e. ₹1.5 lakh,
which the nominee will continue to receive every month.
Ok?  Now if we had
watched the video carefully then we know that I had
told that the monthly income increase will be at the
rate of 5%.  The
company will have the compound annually.  When death occurs, it will
start reaching the nominee.
But how long will the maximum limit be?  That will happen only
till the monthly income becomes one and a half times.
Now because 4 years were completed.  To be
compounded at the rate of 5%.  There is a monthly income benefit of ₹1 lakh.
So it becomes ₹5,000.  So the
year end became ₹15,000.  If you
withdraw 5% of ₹15,000, you will get ₹5250.  If
we add this to ₹15,000, it will become
₹1250.  Then we will apply 5%
rate of interest on this.  Ok?  So the
amount will be ₹5512.50.  If we add this
to ₹110,250 then the
amount will come to ₹115,762.51 or you can say around 63.
Now to calculate the interest for the fourth year, if
we take out 5% of ₹115762.51, it will come to ₹5788.13.  If
we add this amount to ₹115762.51, then
this amount comes to around ₹121550.64.  Or we can say
that instead of ₹51.550 we can also consider 5551.
So because four years had been completed.  The
fifth year was going on.  Due to this,
this amount came which was ₹121550 of monthly income
which the nominee got on the first income, rest you have
understood how the compounding is happening here, if we
compound it in the same way then it will keep
increasing and after reaching the final amount it
stops at ₹1.5 lakh, this is how the
benefit is, the rider options in the plan are
Accidental Death and Disability Rider,
Critical Illness Rider, Surgical
Care Rider, Hospital Care Rider,
Accidental Death Benefit Rider, Waiver of
Premium Benefit rider is also available in it,
you
can take any one of these riders.  But you will take Accidental
Death and Disability Benefit Rider.   Will you take
Accidental Death Benefit Rider?
You will be able to take only one of them.
You can find rider information in the Rider Playlist.
Videos will be available.  You check it.
If you don't find the link in the video description, please let us know in the comment section.
I will come with a separate video.
ok sir.  So this was the information about this plan
which I have shared with you in a simple way.
Now if you
check the policy brochure or
check the policy document, you will
understand many things.  Now understand one thing
yourself.  Explain to others also that
insurance is a protection.
Never take incomplete protection.  If the information is clear
then please like and share the video.
Subscribe to the channel and turn on all notification
bells and tell us in the comment section on
which topic you want the next video.
Thank you.  All of you take care of yourselves.